I also want to talk to you about how to write basic command line tools and scripts in Python.
We want to know how to accept command line arguments.
It's pretty useful for a script write you want to interact with the user.
We saw this.rgv, so that's one way of accepting input from the user.
A nice trick for sys.rgv.
We can use a slicing to remove the name of the file because we usually don't care about it, right?
So I can say arguments equal and where would I start my slice?
Which is the first value that we care about at what index?
And go to the variant.
We care about the rest of them.
Now if I, oops, I'm sorry, it was arguments sys.rgv.
So I'll comment that out.
Now if I run this again, we'll see that, oh, okay, this is actually useful.
I didn't get any arguments.
And now I can say, you know, 1, 2, 3.
Hello, goodbye.
And it'll only print out the arguments that were actually useful to me.
Make a new example, our new file here.
We're going to call it input example.py.
To get an interact with user input, we can use the built-in input function in Python.
So I'm going to say that name equals call the built-in input function.
And the argument here is what you want the prompt to look like.
So say hello human.
What is your name?
Generally you want to put a space here so that there's a little bit of spacing.
You can even put a colon or something kind of signify that you want some input here.
And then you can say, you know, print out.
Hello.
Name.
Nice to meet you.
Running this from the command palette.
We'll see that my prompt has changed.
It's a block now.
It's waiting for input.
So I can type my name in here and get my response back.
Note that if you just press enter, you'll get back an empty string.
So when you're taking, when you're accepting user input, it's generally a good idea to do
some validation on it or some syntax checking.